

CEYHUN EMRE ÖZTÜRKElectrical & Electronics Engineer, M.S.

SUMMARY

An expert AI engineer with 7 years' experience in programming languages, who has taken his master's degree in 2023. Well-versed in various programming languages such as Python and MATLAB. 4 years' experience in defense industry. Open for improvement and systematic.

Year of Birth/Place of Birth

1998/ Aydın, Turkey.

Work Experience

September 2023-Present

Expert AI Engineer • ASELSAN

I worked on applying reinforcement learning algorithms to military simulations.

March 2022-August 2023

NLP Research Engineer • ASELSAN

I conducted research in natural language processing.

December 2019–February 2022

System Design Engineer • ASELSAN

I made effectiveness analysis of the defense systems and I designed the subsystems of the air defense systems.

June 2019-July 2019

Systems Engineering Intern • ASELSAN

I conducted various tests on military radios at the Avionic Communication Systems Engineering Department.

June 2018-July 2018

Research Intern • TÜBİTAK SAGE

I designed interface modules using VHDL and Verilog HDL such that these modules will be used on a type of FPGA which is connected to a QDR II+ SRAM type and I tested these modules by simulation.

Education

- 2020-2023: Bilkent University, Ankara, Turkey.
 M.S. in Electrical and Electronics Engineering (GPA: 3.44/4)
 Thesis title: Retrieving Turkish Prior Legal Cases with Deep Learning
- 2016-2020: Bilkent University, Ankara, Turkey.
 B.S. in Electrical and Electronics Engineering (GPA: 3.55/4)
- 2012-2016: Aydın High School of Science, Aydın, Turkey.

Computer Skills

Turkish: Mother Tongue,

Windows, Ubuntu; Microsoft Office, LaTeX; Python, Tensorflow, Pytorch, MATLAB, Simulink, C++, C, Java.

English: TOEFL iBT (2022): 104/120,

Achievements

- GRE General Test (2019): Qualitative: 169/170, Verbal: 158/170.
- ALES 2019 (Nationwide Academic Personnel and Postgraduate Education Entrance Exam): Ranked 87th in Turkey.
- Comprehensive Scholarship in Bilkent University: I gained this scholarship as a result of my rank in LYS 2016.
- LYS 2016 (Nationwide University Entrance Exam): Ranked 234th in Turkey.



ceyhunemreozturk@hotmail.com

linkedin.com/in/ceyhunemreozturk



Languages

German: A2



Publications

- [1] C. E. Öztürk, Ş. B. Özçelik and A. Koç, " A Transformer-based Prior Legal Case Retrieval Method," 2023 31st Signal Processing and Communications Applications Conference (SIU), 2023.
- [2] C. E. Öztürk, E. H. Yılmaz, and Ö. Köksal, "Transformer-based Bug/Feature Classification," 2023 31st Signal Processing and Communications Applications Conference (SIU), 2023.
- [3] C. E. Öztürk, E. H. Yılmaz, Ö. Köksal, and A. Koç, "Software Module Classification for Commercial Bug Reports", 2023 IEEE International Conference on Acoustics, Speech, and Signal Processing Workshops (ICASSPW), Rhodes Island, Greece, 2023, pp. 1-5.
- [4] C. E. Öztürk, Ö. Köksal, Ş. B. Özçelik and A. Koç, "Prior Case Retrieval for the Court of Cassation of Turkey", 2022 16th International Conference on Signal Image Technology & Internet Based Systems (SITIS), 2022, pp. 539-544.
- [5] Ö. Köksal and **C. E. Öztürk**, "A Survey on Machine Learning-based Automated Software Bug Report Classification," *2022 International Symposium on Multidisciplinary Studies and Innovative Technologies (ISMSIT)*, Dijon, France, 2022, pp. 635-640.
- [6] A. C. Aras, C. E. Öztürk and A. Koç, "Feedforward Neural Network Based Case Prediction in Turkish Higher Courts," 2022 30th Signal Processing and Communications Applications Conference (SIU), 2022, pp. 1-4.
- [7] C. E. Öztürk, Ş. B. Özçelik and A. Koç, "Predicting Outcomes of the Court of Cassation of Turkey with Recurrent Neural Networks," 2022 30th Signal Processing and Communications Applications Conference (SIU), 2022, pp. 1-4.
- [8] E. Mumcuoglu, C. E. Öztürk, H. M. Ozaktas and A. Koç, "Natural Language Processing in Law: Prediction of outcomes in the Higher Courts of Turkey", *Information Processing and Management*, vol. 58, No. 5: 102684, 2021.

Publications under Review

- [1] F. Şahinuç, C. E. Öztürk, and A. Koç, "Dynamic Sense-Structured Multimodal Gaussian Word Embeddings", IEEE/ACM Transactions on Neural Networks and Learning Systems (TNNLS), Submitted: 2023.
- [2] C. E. Öztürk, Ş. B. Özçelik and A. Koç, "Prior Court Case Retrieval with Sentence Transformers in Turkish Courts", IEEE/ACM Transactions on Audio Speech and Language Processing (TASLP), Submitted: 2022.

Teaching

- 2020-2023: Homework grader of the EEE 391 course (Basics of Signals and Systems) at Bilkent University, Ankara, Turkey.
- 2023 Spring: Homework grader of the EEE 486 course (Natural Language Processing) at Bilkent University, Ankara, Turkey.

Social Activities

- 2017-2020: Member of Bilkent IEEE Student Branch.
- 2017-2018: Events Coordinator of Bilkent Free Software Community (Bilkent GNU).
- 2016-2017: Volunteer at the TDP community of Bilkent University. I gave lectures for free to the students who were going to high school or elementary school or middle school.
- 2013-2016: Licensed table tennis player for Aydın High School of Science.

References

Contact information of the references can be provided if needed.



